{
    
    "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
    "name": "Threaded and Grooved Pipe : Part 1",
    "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
    "questions": [
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the Std abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Standard", "standard"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the XS abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Extra Strong", "extra strong", "Extra strong"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the XXH abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Double Extra Heavy", "Double extra heavy", "double extra heavy"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the XH abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Extra Heavy", "Extra heavy", "extra heavy"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the XXS abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Double Extra Strong", "Double extra strong", "double extra strong"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
        {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the Sch abbreviation used to describe steel pipe stand for?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Schedule", "schedule"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the difference between inside diameter and nominal pipe size?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Inside diameter is the outer measurement of the pipe, while NPS is the inner measurement.",
               "Inside diameter is used for calculating pressure, while NPS is used for determining flow rate.",
               "Inside diameter is the measurement from the outer edge of the pipe, while NPS is the thickness of the pipe.",
               "Inside diameter is the same as the pipe's wall thickness, while NPS is an industry standard measurement.",
             "Inside diameter is the actual measurement between the inside walls of the pipe across the exact center. NPS is an approximation of the inside diameter; it is an industry standard used to identify various pipe sizes."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Inside diameter is the actual measurement between the inside walls of the pipe across the exact center. NPS is an approximation of the inside diameter; it is an industry standard used to identify various pipe sizes."],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the difference between black iron pipe and galvanized iron pipe?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Black iron pipe is made from a different material than galvanized iron pipe.",
               "Black iron pipe is used for gas lines, while galvanized iron pipe is used for water lines.",
               "Black iron pipe has shellac or varnish applied for protection. Galvanized iron pipe has a zinc coating applied by hot dipping the black pipe to provide 2 oz per square foot of coating inside and outside.",
               "Black iron pipe is stronger than galvanized iron pipe.",
               "Black iron pipe is heavier than galvanized iron pipe."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Black iron pipe has shellac or varnish applied for protection. Galvanized iron pipe has a zinc coating applied by hot dipping the black pipe to provide 2 oz per square foot of coating inside and outside."],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "A 2'' NPS has an actual inside diameter of 2.067'' and a wall thickness of exactly 0.154''. What is the exact outside diameter of the pipe?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["2.375", "2 3/8", "2,375"],
           "explanation": "2.067 + 0.154 + 0.154 = 2.375 or 2 3/8. Note that the pipe has 2 wall thicknesses"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "A 10'' NPS pipe has an actual OD of 10.75'' and an actual ID of 9.75''. What grade of pipe is this?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["Sch 60", "60", "XS", "Sch. 60"],
           "explanation": "Grade = Sch. 60 or XS"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "A 10'' NPS pipe has an actual OD of 10.75'' and an actual ID of 9.75''. What is its wall thickness (WT)?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["0.5", "0,5"],
           "explanation": "WT = 10.75'' - 9.75'' = 1.0'' / 2 = 0.5''"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 1.610 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145"],
           "explanation": "1.610 ID - Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 1.049 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"],
           "explanation": "1.049 ID - Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 1.278 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191"],
           "explanation": "1.278 ID - Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 0.599 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358"],
           "explanation": "0.599 ID - Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 7.625 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500"],
           "explanation": "7.625 ID - Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 2.300 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600"],
           "explanation": "2.300 ID - Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The table below lists the actual pipe sizes of several different pipes. Select the Grade, NPS, and the WT of the pipes: 0.252 ID - Grade ____, NPS ____, WT ________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Grade XXS, NPS 3, WT 0.600",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1 1/2, WT 0.145",
               "Grade XS/Sch80, NPS 1 1/4, WT 0.191",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1, WT 0.358",
               "Grade Std/Sch80, NPS 8, WT 0.500",
               "Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294",
               "Grade Std/Sch40, NPS 1, WT 0.133"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294"],
           "explanation": "0.252 ID - Grade XXS, NPS 1/2, WT 0.294"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "Which grade of threaded pipe should be used with the following maximum pressures? 1000 psi",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Std/Sch 40",
               "XS/Sch 80",
               "XXS"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["XXS"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "Which grade of threaded pipe should be used with the following maximum pressures? 150 psi",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
             "Std/Sch 40",
             "XS/Sch 80",
             "XXS"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Std/Sch 40"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "Which grade of threaded pipe should be used with the following maximum pressures? 200 psi",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Std/Sch 40",
               "XS/Sch 80",
               "XXS"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["XS/Sch 80"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the approximate percent of carbon in the iron used to produce the following products? Steel pipes",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
             "0.1 to 0.2% carbon",
             "1.5% carbon",
             "1.8 to 4.8% carbon",
             "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the approximate percent of carbon in the iron used to produce the following products? Files",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "0.1 to 0.2% carbon",
               "1.5% carbon",
               "1.8 to 4.8% carbon",
               "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "1.5% carbon"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the approximate percent of carbon in the iron used to produce the following products? Cast iron",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "0.1 to 0.2% carbon",
               "1.5% carbon",
               "1.8 to 4.8% carbon",
               "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "1.8 to 4.8% carbon"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the approximate percent of carbon in the iron used to produce the following products? Sheet steel",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "0.2 to 0.1% carbon",
               "1.5% carbon",
               "1.8 to 4.8% carbon",
               "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "0.1 to 0.2% carbon"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What does the schedule number of a pipe designate?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "The schedule number of a pipe designates the pipe's wall thickness.",
               "The schedule number of a pipe designates the pipe's diameter.",
               "The schedule number of a pipe designates the pipe's length.",
               "The schedule number of a pipe designates the pipe's weight.",
               "The schedule number of a pipe designates the pressure/stress ratio X 1000."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["The schedule number of a pipe designates the pressure/stress ratio X 1000."],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "At what size for standard pipe does the wall thickness remain the same for increases in pipe size?",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["12"],
           "explanation": "Size = 12"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "At what size for standard pipe does the wall thickness remain the same for increases in pipe size and what is the WT? Write WT only",
           "type": "text_type",
           "options": [],
           "correctAnswer": ["0.375", "0,375"],
           "explanation": "WT = 0.375"
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is meant by the term alloy as applied to the manufacture of ferrous pipe?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Alloys are metal(s) mixed with iron to produce special qualities in pipe.",
               "Alloys are non-metallic elements added to iron to increase durability.",
               "Alloys are iron pipes coated with a layer of another metal.",
               "Alloys are pipes made from recycled iron and steel materials.",
               "Alloys are iron pipes that have been heat-treated for added strength."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Alloys are metal(s) mixed with iron to produce special qualities in pipe."],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "List three (3) different types of alloyed steel pipe and state the alloying materials used.",
           "type": "checkbox_type",
           "options": [
             "Copper-bearing alloys - min. 0.25% copper.",
             "Stainless steel - chromium and nickel.",
             "Chrome/moly - chromium and molybdenum."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "Copper-bearing alloys - min. 0.25% copper.",
             "Stainless steel - chromium and nickel.",
             "Chrome/moly - chromium and molybdenum."
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "List four (4) common end finishes applied to steel pipe.",
           "type": "checkbox_type",
           "options": [
             "Plain end.",
             "Threaded.",
             "Bevelled end.",
             "Threaded and coupled.",
             "Grooved."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "Plain end.",
             "Threaded.",
             "Bevelled end.",
             "Threaded and coupled.",
             "Grooved."
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "List four (4) common surface finishes applied to steel pipe before delivery.",
           "type": "checkbox_type",
           "options": [
             "Plain end.",
             "Threaded.",
             "Bevelled end.",
             "Threaded and coupled.",
             "Grooved."
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "Plain end.",
             "Threaded.",
             "Bevelled end.",
             "Threaded and coupled.",
             "Grooved."
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The distance from the crest of one thread to the crest of the next thread is called the:_______",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "the height of the thread",
               "the depth of the thread",
               "the angle of the thread",
               "the root of the thread",
             "the pitch of the thread"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["the pitch of the thread"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the difference between male and female threads?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Male threads are larger than female threads.",
               "Male threads are more durable than female threads.",
               "Male threads are used for gas connections, while female threads are used for water connections.",
               "Male threads are tapered, while female threads are straight.",
             "Male threads are on the external or outer surface of the pipe, while female threads are internal or inner surface of the fitting"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Male threads are on the external or outer surface of the pipe, while female threads are internal or inner surface of the fitting"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The thread on the inside wall of a fitting is referred to as a/an:",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "a female tapered thread or F.I.P. female iron pipe thread",
               "external thread or male thread",
               "parallel thread",
               "buttress thread"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["a female tapered thread or F.I.P. female iron pipe thread"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "The thread cut with standard dies on the outside wall of a pipe is referred to as a/an:",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "a male tapered thread or M.I.P. female iron pipe thread",
               "internal thread or male thread",
               "tapered thread",
               "parallel thread",
               "buttress thread"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["a male tapered thread or M.I.P. female iron pipe thread"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "When tightening a fitting onto a pipe, the fitting should be turned by hand approximately ______ to ______ times and made up with the aid of a wrench approximately __________ to ____________",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
             "4 to 5 times, 2 to 3 turns",
             "4 to 6 3/4 times, 1 to 2 turns",
             "4 to 6 3/4 times, 2 to 3 turns",
             "1 to 2 times, 2 to 3 turns"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["4 to 6 3/4 times, 2 to 3 turns"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "Why are pipe threads tapered and how much does this taper amount to if extended to one foot in length?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Pipe threads are tapered to allow for easy disassembly. The taper amounts to 1/2 per foot.",
               "Pipe threads are tapered to prevent leakage. The taper amounts to 1/4 per foot.",
               "Pipe threads are tapered to increase strength. The taper amounts to 1 per foot.",
               "Pipe threads are tapered to facilitate threading. The taper amounts to 1/8 per foot.",
             "Pipe threads are tapered so that the pipe will tighten into fittings. The taper amount is 3/4 increase in diameter at 12"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Pipe threads are tapered so that the pipe will tighten into fittings. The taper amount is 3/4 increase in diameter at 12"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "Define the term throw as it applies to pipe fittings.",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "The angle at which a pipe fitting changes direction",
               "The length of the threaded portion of a pipe fitting",
               "The distance measured from the centre to the face of fittings",
               "The diameter of the opening in a pipe fitting",
               "The thickness of the walls of a pipe fitting"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["The distance measured from the centre to the face of fittings"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "List five (5) different methods of taking pipe measurements.",
           "type": "checkbox_type",
           "options": [
             "Using a pipe caliper",
             "Using a tape measure",
             "Using a pipe diameter tape",
             "Using a ruler",
             "Using a laser distance measurer"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "Using a pipe caliper",
             "Using a tape measure",
             "Using a pipe diameter tape",
             "Using a ruler",
             "Using a laser distance measurer"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "What is the difference between a coupling and a thread protector?",
           "type": "single_type",
           "options": [
               "Couplings have tapered threads; thread protectors have parallel threads",
               "Couplings are used to join two pipes; thread protectors are used to seal pipe ends",
               "Couplings are made of metal; thread protectors are made of plastic",
               "Couplings are permanent fittings; thread protectors are temporary fittings",
               "Couplings have internal threads; thread protectors have external threads"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": ["Couplings have tapered threads; thread protectors have parallel threads"],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
           "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
           "question": "List four (4) reasons for flushing oil over a pipe thread that is being cut.",
           "type": "checkbox_type",
           "options": [
             "To cool the cutting tool and pipe",
             "To remove metal shavings",
             "To prevent rust",
             "To lubricate the cutting process"
           ],
           "correctAnswer": [
             "To cool the cutting tool and pipe",
             "To remove metal shavings",
             "To prevent rust",
             "To lubricate the cutting process"
           ],
           "explanation": ""
         },
         {
            "id": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
            "topicId": "e0b1c02c-2a7e-11ec-8d3d-0242ac130003",
            "question": "Burrs should be removed from the inside walls of pipe. List three (3) problems that can occur if burrs are not removed.",
            "type": "checkbox_type",
            "options": [
              "Restricted flow",
              "Damage to the pipe interior",
              "Compromised thread integrity"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": [
              "Restricted flow",
              "Damage to the pipe interior",
              "Compromised thread integrity"
            ],
            "explanation": ""
          }
    ]
}
